In the last few videos, we talked
在上面几个视频中 我们讨论了
about stochastic gradient descent, and,
随机梯度下降
you know, other variations of the
以及梯度下降算法的
stochastic gradient descent algorithm,
其他一些变种
including those adaptations to online
包括如何将其
learning, but all of those
运用于在线学习
algorithms could be run on
然而所有这些算法
one machine, or could be run on one computer.
都只能在一台计算机上运行
And some machine learning problems
但是 有些机器学习问题
are just too big to run
太大以至于不可能
on one machine, sometimes maybe
只在一台计算机上运行
you just so much data you
有时候 它涉及的数据量如此巨大
just don't ever want to run
以至于不论你使用何种算法
all that data through a
你都不希望只使用
single computer, no matter what algorithm you would use on that computer.
一台计算机来处理这些数据
So in this video I'd
因此 在这个视频中
like to talk about different approach
我希望介绍
to large scale machine learning, called
进行大规模机器学习的另一种方法
the map reduce approach.
称为映射约减 (map reduce) 方法
And even though we have
尽管我们
quite a few videos on stochastic
用了多个视频讲解
gradient descent and we're going
随机梯度下降算法
to spend relative less time
而我们将只用少量时间
on map reduce--don't judge the
介绍映射化简
relative importance of map reduce
但是请不要根据
versus the gradient descent
我们所花的时间长短
based on the amount amount of
来判断哪一种技术
time I spend on these ideas in particular.
更加重要
Many people will say that
事实上 许多人认为
map reduce is at least
映射化简方法至少是
an equally important, and some
同等重要的
would say an even more important idea
还有人认为映射化简方法
compared to gradient descent, only
甚至比梯度下降方法更重要
it's relatively simpler to
我们之所以只在
explain, which is why I'm
映射化简上花的时间比较少
going to spend less time on
只是因为它相对简单 容易解释
it, but using these ideas
然而 实际上
you might be able to scale
相比于随机梯度下降方法
learning algorithms to even
映射化简方法
far larger problems than is
能够处理
possible using stochastic gradient descent.
更大规模的问题
Here's the idea.
这个方法如下
Let's say we want to fit
假设我们要
a linear regression model or
拟合一个线性回归模型
a logistic regression model or some
或者逻辑回归模型
such, and let's start again
或者其他的什么模型
with batch gradient descent, so
让我们再次从随机梯度下降算法开始吧
that's our batch gradient descent learning rule.
这就是我们的随机梯度下降学习算法
And to keep the writing
为了让幻灯片上的文字
on this slide tractable, I'm going
更容易理解
to assume throughout that we have m equals 400 examples.
我们将假定m固定为400个样本
Of course, by our
当然 根据
standards, in terms of large scale
大规模机器学习的标准
machine learning, you know m
m等于400
might be pretty small and so,
实在是太小了
this might be more commonly
也许在实际问题中
applied to problems, where you
你更有可能遇到
have maybe closer to 400
样本大小为4亿
million examples, or some
的数据
such, but just to
或者其他差不多的大小
make the writing on the slide
但是 为了使我们的讲解更加简单和清晰
simpler, I'm going to pretend we have 400 examples.
我们假定我们只有400个样本
So in that case, the
这样一来
batch gradient descent learning rule
随机梯度下降学习算法中
has this 400 and the
这里是400
sum from i equals 1 through
以及400个样本的求和
400 through my 400 examples
这里i从1取到400
here, and if m
如果m很大
is large, then this is a computationally expensive step.
那么这一步的计算量将会很大
So, what the MapReduce idea
因此 下面我们来介绍
does is the following, and
映射化简算法
I should say the map
这里我必须指出
reduce idea is due to
映射化简算法的基本思想
two researchers, Jeff Dean
来自Jeffrey Dean和Sanjay Ghemawat
and Sanjay Gimawat.
这两位研究者
Jeff Dean, by the way, is
Jeff Dean是硅谷
one of the most legendary engineers in
最为传奇般的
all of Silicon Valley and he
一位工程师
kind of built a large
今天谷歌 (Google) 所有的服务
fraction of the architectural
所依赖的后台基础架构
infrastructure that all of Google runs on today.
有很大一部分是他创建的
But here's the map reduce idea.
扯远了 我们还是回到映射化简的基本思想
So, let's say I have
假设我们有一个
some training set, if we
训练样本
want to denote by this box here
我们将它表示为
of X Y pairs,
这个方框中的一系列x~y数据对
where it's X1, Y1, down
从x(1) y(1)开始
to my 400 examples,
涵盖我所有的400个样本
Xm, Ym.
直到x(m) y(m)
So, that's my training set with 400 training examples.
总之 这就是我的400个训练样本
In the MapReduce idea, one way
根据映射化简的思想
to do, is split this training
一种解决方案是
set in to different subsets.
将训练集划分成几个不同的子集
I'm going to.
好 我们基本上已经讲完了两本书
assume for this example that
我假定我有
I have 4 computers,
4台计算机
or 4 machines to run in
它们并行的
parallel on my training set,
处理我的训练数据
which is why I'm splitting this into 4 machines.
因此我要将数据划分成4份 分给这4台计算机
If you have 10 machines or
如果你有10台计算机
100 machines, then you would
或者100台计算机
split your training set into 10 pieces or 100 pieces or what have you.
那么你可能会将训练数据划分成10份或者100份
And what the first of my
我的4台计算机中
4 machines is to do,
第一台
say, is use just the
将处理第一个
first one quarter of my
四分之一训练数据
training set--so use just the first 100 training examples.
也就是前100个训练样本
And in particular, what it's
具体来说
going to do is look at
这台计算机
this summation, and compute
将参与处理这个求和
that summation for just the first 100 training examples.
它将对前100个训练样本进行求和运算
So let me write that up
让我把公式写下来吧
I'm going to compute a variable
我将计算临时变量
temp 1 to superscript 1
temp(1) 这里的上标(1)
the first machine J equals
表示第一台计算机
sum from equals 1 through
其下标为j 该变量等于从1到100的求和
100, and then I'm going to plug
然后我在这里写的部分
in exactly that term there--so I have
和这里的完全相同
X-theta, Xi, minus Yi
也就是h_θ(x(i))-y(i)
times Xij, right?
乘以x(i)j
So that's just that
这其实就是
gradient descent term up there.
这里的梯度下降公式中的这一项
And then similarly, I'm going
然后 类似地
to take the second quarter
我将用第二台计算机
of my data and send it
处理我的
to my second machine, and
第二个四分之一数据
my second machine will use
也就是说 我的第二台计算机
training examples 101 through 200
将使用第101到200号训练样本
and you will compute similar variables
类似地 我们用它
of a temp to j which
计算临时变量 temp(2)_j
is the same sum for index
也就是从101到200号
from examples 101 through 200.
数据的求和
And similarly machines 3
类似的 第三台和第四台
and 4 will use the
计算机将会使用
third quarter and the fourth
第三个和第四个
quarter of my training set.
四分之一训练样本
So now each machine has
这样 现在每台计算机
to sum over 100 instead
不用处理400个样本
of over 400 examples and so
而只用处理100个样本
has to do only a quarter
它们只用完成
of the work and thus presumably
四分之一的工作量
it could do it about four times as fast.
这样 也许可以将运算速度提高到原来的四倍
Finally, after all these machines
最后 当这些计算机
have done this work, I am
全都完成了各自的工作
going to take these temp variables
我会将这些临时变量
and put them back together.
收集到一起
So I take these variables and
我会将它们
send them all to a You
送到一个
know centralized master server and
中心计算服务器
what the master will do
这台服务器会
is combine these results together.
将这些临时变量合并起来
and in particular, it will
具体来说
update my parameters theta
它将根据以下公式
j according to theta
来更新参数θj
j gets updated as theta j
新的θj将等于
minus Of the
旧的θj减去
learning rate alpha times one
学习速率α乘以
over 400 times temp,
400分之一
1, J, plus temp
乘以临时变量 temp(1)_j
2j plus temp 3j
加temp(2)_j 加temp(3)_j
plus temp 4j and
加temp(4)_j
of course we have to do this separately for J equals 0.
当然 对于j等于0的情况我们需要单独处理
You know, up to
这里 j从0
and within this number of features.
取到特征总数n
So operating this equation into I hope it's clear.
通过将这个公式拆成多行讲解 我希望大家已经理解了
So what this equation
其实 这个公式计算的数值
is doing is exactly the
和原先的梯度下降公式计算的数值
same is that when you
是完全一样的
have a centralized master server
只不过 现在我们有一个中心运算服务器
that takes the results, the ten
它收集了一些部分计算结果
one j the ten two j
temp(1)_j temp(2)_j
ten three j and ten four
temp(3)_j 和 temp(4)_j
j and adds them up
把它们加了起来
and so of course the sum
很显然 这四个
of these four things.
临时变量的和
Right, that's just the sum of
就是这个求和
this, plus the sum
加上这个求和
of this, plus the sum
再加上这个求和
of that, and those four
它们加起来的和
things just add up to
其实和原先
be equal to this sum that
我们使用批量梯度下降公式
we're originally computing a batch stream descent.
计算的结果是一样的
And then we have the alpha times
接下来 我们有
1 of 400, alpha times 1
α乘以400分之一
of 100, and this is
这里也是α乘以400分之一
exactly equivalent to the
因此这个公式
batch gradient descent algorithm, only,
完全等同于批量梯度下降公式
instead of needing to sum
唯一的不同是
over all four hundred training
我们原本需要在一台计算机上
examples on just one
完成400个训练样本的求和
machine, we can instead
而现在
divide up the work load on four machines.
我们将这个工作分给了4台计算机
So, here's what the general
总结来说
picture of the MapReduce technique looks like.
映射约减技术是这么工作的
We have some training sets, and
我们有一些训练样本
if we want to paralyze across four
如果我们希望使用4台计算机
machines, we are going to
并行的运行机器学习算法
take the training set and split it, you know, equally.
那么我们将训练样本等分
Split it as evenly as we can into four subsets.
尽量均匀地分成4份
Then we are going to take the
然后 我们将这4个
4 subsets of the training data and send them to 4 different computers.
训练样本的子集送给4台不同的计算机
And each of the 4 computers
每一台计算机
can compute a summation over
对四分之一的
just one quarter of the
训练数据
training set, and then
进行求和运算
finally take each of
最后 这4个求和结果
the computers takes the results, sends
被送到一台中心计算服务器
them to a centralized server, which then combines the results together.
负责对结果进行汇总
So, on the previous line
在前一张幻灯片中
in that example, the bulk
在那个例子中
of the work in gradient descent,
梯度下降计算
was computing the sum from
的内容是对i等于1到400的
i equals 1 to 400 of something.
400个样本进行求和运算
So more generally, sum from
更宽泛的来讲 在梯度下降计算中
i equals 1 to m
我们是对i等于1到m的m个样本
of that formula for gradient descent.
进行求和
And now, because each of
现在 因为这4台计算机
the four computers can do just
的每一台都可以
a quarter of the work, potentially
完成四分之一的计算工作
you can get up to a 4x speed up.
因此你可能会得到4倍的加速
In particular, if there were
特别的
no network latencies and
如果没有网络延时
no costs of the network
也不考虑
communications to send the
通过网络来回传输数据
data back and forth, you can
所消耗的时间
potentially get up to a 4x speed up.
那么你可能可以得到4倍的加速
Of course, in practice,
当然 在实际工作中
because of network latencies,
因为网络延时
the overhead of combining the
数据汇总额外消耗时间
results afterwards and other factors,
以及其他的一些因素
in practice you get slightly less than a 4x speedup.
你能得到的加速总是略小于4倍的
But, none the less, this sort
但是 不管怎么说
of macro juice approach does offer
这种映射化简算法
us a way to process much
确实让我们能够处理
larger data sets than is
将能够处理
possible using a single computer.
所无法处理的大规模数据
If you are thinking of applying
如果你打算
Map Reduce to some learning
将映射化简技术用于
algorithm, in order to speed this up.
加速某个机器学习算法
By paralleling the computation
也就是说 你打算运用多台不同的计算机
over different computers, the key
并行的进行计算
question to ask yourself is,
那么你需要问自己一个很关键的问题
can your learning algorithm be expressed
那就是 你的机器学习算法
as a summation over the training set?
是否可以表示为训练样本的某种求和
And it turns out that many
事实证明
learning algorithms can actually be
很多机器学习算法
expressed as computing sums of
的确可以表示为
functions over the training set and
关于训练样本的函数求和
the computational expense of running
而在处理大数据时
them on large data sets is
这些算法的主要运算量
because they need to sum over a very large training set.
在于对大量训练数据求和
So, whenever your learning algorithm
因此 只要你的机器学习算法
can be expressed as a
可以表示为
sum of the training set
训练样本的一个求和
and whenever the bulk of the
只要算法的
work of the learning algorithm
主要计算部分
can be expressed as the sum
可以表示为
of the training set, then map
训练样本的求和
reviews might a good candidate
那么你可以考虑使用映射化简技术
for scaling your learning algorithms through very, very good data sets.
来将你的算法扩展到非常大规模的数据上
Lets just look at one more example.
让我们再看一个例子
Let's say that we want to use one of the advanced optimization algorithm.
假设我们想使用某种高级优化算法
So, things like, you
比如说
know, l, b, f, g, s constant
LBFGS算法
gradient and so on, and
或者共轭梯度算法等等
let's say we want to train a logistic regression of the algorithm.
假设我们想使用逻辑回归算法
For that, we need to compute two main quantities.
于是 我们需要计算两个值
One is for the advanced
对于LBFGS算法和共轭梯度算法
optimization algorithms like, you know, LPF and constant gradient.
我们需要计算的第一个值是
We need to provide it a
我们需要提供一种方法
routine to compute the
用于计算
cost function of the optimization objective.
优化目标的代价函数值
And so for logistic regression, you
比如 对于逻辑回归
remember that a cost function
你应该记得它的代价函数
has this sort of sum over
可以表示为
the training set, and so
训练样本上的这种求和
if youre paralizing over
因此 如果你想在
ten machines, you would split
10台计算机上并行计算
up the training set onto ten
那么你需要将训练样本
machines and have each
分给这10台计算机
of the ten machines compute the sum
让每台计算机
of this quantity over just
计算10份之一
one tenth of the training
训练数据的
data.
是异常困难的
Then, the other thing that the
高级优化算法
advanced optimization algorithms need,
还需要提供
is a routine to compute
这些偏导数
these partial derivative terms.
的计算方法
Once again, these derivative terms, for
同样的 对于逻辑回归
which it's a logistic regression, can
这些偏导数
be expressed as a sum over
可以表示为
the training set, and so once
训练数据的求和
again, similar to our earlier
因此 和之前的例子类似
example, you would have
你可以让
each machine compute that summation
每台计算机只计算
over just some small fraction of your training data.
部分训练数据上的求和
And finally, having computed
最后 当这些求和计算完成之后
all of these things, they could
求和结果
then send their results to
会被发送到
a centralized server, which can
一台中心计算服务器上
then add up the partial sums.
这台服务器将对结果进行再次求和
This corresponds to adding up
这等同于
those tenth i or
对临时变量temp(i)
tenth ij variables, which
或者 temp(i)_j 进行求和
were computed locally on machine
而这些临时标量
number i, and so
是第i台计算机算出来的
the centralized server can sum
中心计算服务器
these things up and get
对这些临时变量求和
the overall cost function
得到了总的代价函数值
and get the overall partial derivative,
以及总的偏导数值
which you can then pass through the advanced optimization algorithm.
然后你可以将这两个值传给高级优化函数
So, more broadly, by taking
因此 更广义的来说
other learning algorithms and
通过将机器学习算法
expressing them in sort of
表示为
summation form or by expressing
求和的形式
them in terms of computing sums
或者是
of functions over the training set,
训练数据的函数求和形式
you can use the MapReduce technique to
你就可以运用映射化简技术
parallelize other learning algorithms as well,
来将算法并行化
and scale them to very large training sets.
这样就可以处理大规模数据了
Finally, as one last comment,
最后再提醒一点
so far we have been
目前我们只讨论了
discussing MapReduce algorithms as
运用映射化简技术
allowing you to parallelize over
在多台计算机上
multiple computers, maybe multiple
实现并行计算
computers in a computer
也许是一个计算机集群
cluster or over multiple computers in the data center.
也许是一个数据中心中的多台计算机
It turns out that sometimes even
但实际上
if you have just a single computer,
有时即使我们只有一台计算机
MapReduce can also be applicable.
我们也可以运用这种技术
In particular, on many single
具体来说
computers now, you can have
现在的许多计算机
multiple processing cores.
都是多核的
You can have multiple CPUs,
你可以有多个CPU
and within each CPU you can
而每个CPU
have multiple proc cores.
又包括多个核
If you have a large training
如果你有一个
set, what you can
很大的训练样本
do if, say, you have
那么你可以
a computer with 4
使用一台
computing cores, what you
四核的计算机
can do is, even on a
即使在这样一台计算机上
single computer you can split the
你依然可以
training sets into pieces and
将训练样本分成几份
send the training set to different
然后让每一个核
cores within a single box,
处理其中一份子样本
like within a single desktop computer
这样 在单台计算机
or a single server and use
或者单个服务器上
MapReduce this way to divvy up work load.
你也可以利用映射化简技术来划分计算任务
Each of the cores can then
每一个核
carry out the sum over,
可以处理
say, one quarter of your
比方说四分之一
training set, and then they
训练样本的求和
can take the partial sums and
然后我们再将
combine them, in order
这些部分和汇总
to get the summation over the entire training set.
最终得到整个训练样本上的求和
The advantage of thinking
相对于多台计算机
about MapReduce this way, as
这样在单台计算机上
paralyzing over cause within a
使用映射化简技术
single machine, rather than parallelizing over
的一个优势
multiple machines is that,
在于
this way you don't have to
现在你不需要
worry about network latency, because
担心网络延时问题
all the communication, all the
因为所有的通讯
sending of the  [xx]
所有的来回数据传输
back and forth, all that happens within a single machine.
都发生在一台计算机上
And so network latency becomes
因此 相比于使用数据中心的
much less of an issue compared
多台计算机
to if you were using this
现在网络延时的影响
to over different computers within the data sensor.
小了许多
Finally, one last caveat on
最后 关于在一台多核计算机上的并行运算
parallelizing within a multi-core machine.
我再提醒一点
Depending on the details
这取决于你的编程实现细节
of your implementation, if you have a
如果你有一台
multi-core machine and if you
多核计算机
have certain numerical linear algebra libraries.
并且使用了某个线性代数函数库
It turns out that the sum numerical linear algebra libraries
那么请注意 某些线性代数函数库
that can automatically parallelize their
会自动利用多个核
linear algebra operations across multiple cores within the machine.
并行地完成线性代数运算
So if you're fortunate enough to
因此 如果你幸运地
be using one of those numerical linear algebra
使用了这种
libraries and certainly
线性代数函数库
this does not apply to every single library.
当然 并不是每个函数库都会自动并行
If you're using one of those libraries and.
但如果你用了这样一个函数库
If you have a very good vectorizing implementation of the learning algorithm.
并且你有一个矢量化得很好的算法实现
Sometimes you can just implement
那么 有时你只需要
you standard learning algorithm in
按照标准的矢量化方式
a vectorized fashion and not
实现机器学习算法
worry about parallelization and numerical linear algebra libararies
而不用管多核并行的问题
could take care of some of it for you.
因为你的线性代数函数库会自动帮助你完成多核并行的工作
So you don't need to implement [xx] but.
因此 这时你不需要使用映射化简技术
for other any problems, taking advantage
但是 对于其他的问题
of this sort of map reducing commentation,
使用基于映射化简的实现
finding and using this
寻找并使用
MapReduce formulation and to
适合映射化简的问题表述
paralelize a cross coarse except
然后实现一个
yourself might be a
多核并行的算法
good idea as well and could let you speed up your learning algorithm.
可能是个好主意 它将会加速你的机器学习算法
In this video, we talked about
在这个视频中
the MapReduce approach to parallelizing
我们介绍了映射化简(map reduce)技术
machine learning by taking a
它可以通过
data and spreading them across
将数据分配到多台计算机的方式
many computers in the data center.
来并行化机器学习算法
Although these ideas are
实际上这种方法
critical to paralysing across multiple
也可以利用
cores within a single computer
单台计算机的多个核
as well.
广告
Today there are some good
今天 网上有许多优秀的
open source implementations of MapReduce,
开源映射化简实现
so there are many users
实际上 一个称为Hadoop
in open source system called
的开源系统
Hadoop and using either your
已经拥有了众多的用户
own implementation or using someone
通过自己实现映射化简算法
else's open source implementation, you
或者使用别人的开源实现
can use these ideas to
你就可以利用映射化简技术
parallelize learning algorithms and
来并行化机器学习算法
get them to run on much
这样你的算法
larger data sets than is
将能够处理
possible using just a single machine.
单台计算机处理不了的大数据 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：王祖超 校对/审核：所罗门捷列夫